Uma Rama Linga Murthy Marthi

Lead Business Analyst



About Me

As a cloud based data science professional with over a decade of experience, having built, deployed and maintained 50+ dashboards, led machine learning projects with expertise in Qlik, PowerBI, Python, AI, ML and NLP, am eager to collaborate with industry-leading professionals, drawn to opportunities that involve tackling the most critical business challenges.

Areas of Specialization

ETL • Business Intelligence · Data Science

- · Machine Learning
- · Deep Learning · Natural Language Processing (NLP) · Computer Vision
- · DevOps · MLOps · Data **Pipelines**

Personal

Nationality: India Date Of Birth: 10/03/1987

Place Of Birth: Hyderabad

Interests

Reading Books **Badminton** Traveling

Languages

Telugu	mother tongue				
Hindi	•	•	•	•	-
English	•	•	•	•	
Tamil	•	•	•	•	

DEGREES

Data Science and Engineering М.Тесн., · BITS, Pilani 🚊



2010 **Finance and Marketing**

PGDM., · SSIM, Hyderabad 🟛



2008 **Mechanical Engineering**

B.TECH., · DMSSVHCE, Machilipatnam m



SKILLS

QlikSense,QlikView Python, PySpark, TF Alteryx,PowerBI,Tableau Apache Kafka, Airflow GitHub,Gitlab,VSCode





CMA CGM

😂 LOHONHUIOW

scintel

Work Experience

2021-Present **CMA CGM GBS INDIA LTD**

LEAD BUSINESS ANALYST · Chennai, India 9

Responsible to generate business use cases with application of Machine learning on global customer data base • Responsible to maintain Global Partner Data Management Dashboards and related dimensions · Lead Global CDM Analytics and data science initiatives managing a team of data



2018-2020 LATENTVIEW ANALYTICS LTD

LEAD DATA ANALYST · Chennai, India 💡

Responsible to collect requirements, project planning, execution and delivery of analytics solutions to clients spread across Insurance and Auto industries.

2016-2018 **SCINTEL TECHNOLOGIES LTD**

SENIOR BUSINESS ANALYST · Chennai, India 💡

Responsible to collect requirements, execution and delivery of Business

Intelligence solutions to clients from Healthcare Industry.

2012-2016 GAFFNEY-KROESE SUPPLY INDIA PVT. LTD.

BUSINESS ANALYST · Chennai, India 💡

Responsible to maintain databases in SQL and prepare reports as per man-

agement needs.

2011-2012 ZENITH ENERGY SERVICES PVT LTD.

Assistant Manager-Renewable Energy · Hyderabad, India 💡

Responsible to conduct MNRE based policy study on biomass and baggasse cogeneration plants across India

2010-2011 NOVUS GREEN ENERGY SYSTEMS PVT LTD.

AREA MANAGER-CHATTISGARH · Raipur, India 💡

Responsible for business development.



zenith energy

VITAL DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

- · 2024: Steel Plate Defect Prediction
- · 2024: Investment Tracking PowerBI Dashboard
- 2024: House Price Prediction with Machine Learning in Kaggle
- · 2023: Bookings Prediction with Deep Learning
- · 2023: Customer Data Replication with GANs
- · 2023: Customer Churn Prediction in Shipping Industry with Machine Learning
- · 2023: Computer Vision based scene text extraction model to extract data for twitter data extraction.
- 2022: NLP Based AI Tool for penny stocks recommendations

VITAL OFFICIAL PROJECTS

- · 2021-2023CMA CGM GBS India Ltd.
- · GANs Based Customer Data Generation Project
- · GBS Performance KPI Dashboard
- · Dimension Partner Dashboard and Ecosystem Maintenance
- · Dimension Partner Summary Dashboard
- · MyCDM Dashboard Database Migration Project
- · Asia Regional Office Finance KPI Dashboard
- QVD Comparison Dashboard
- · 2018-2020 LatentView Analytics Ltd.
- · Crash Data Base Reports
- · Employers Insights Dashboard
- · Clinical Key Performance Indicators (KPI) Return to Health (RTH) Dashboard
- · Clinical Key Performance Indicators (KPI) Higher Level Reviews (HLR)
- · Long Term Care Usual Customary Charges Validation (LTC UCCV Project)
- · 2016-2018 SCINTEL TECHNOLOGIES Ltd.
- Savings Tracker Business Process Modeling, Optimization and Implementation Project
- · Travel Policy Compliance Monitoring
- · 2018-2020Gaffney-Kroese Supply India Pvt. Ltd.
- Sales, Distribution and Supply Chain Management Dashboard
- · Business Intelligence Implementation Project with QlikView

CERTIFICATES

- · 2022: Certified Qlik Data Architect
- **2021**: Advanced Alteryx Core Developer





LINKS

nttps://www.linkedin.com/in/rmarthi-521057138/

https://github.com/RamMarthi9

Ram Marthi ☑ Chennai ♀ India ६ +91 9000 364152 ② ram.marthi@gmail.com